A Guide to the John Barnes Performing Arts Collection, 1890s-1980s
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
John Barnes Performing Arts Collection, 1890-1983 (Bulk, 1940-1696)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Barnes, John H. (John Hancock), 1905-1979
Ms2016-005
11.9 Cubic Feet 9 boxes, 1 oversize folder
The collection includes performing arts programs from around the world as well as scrapbooks and clippings about the theatre and movie industries. The programs cover a variety of genres including theatre, classical and popular music, opera, ballet, motion picture, and other genres such as horse ballet, ice skating, and circus. The programs come from numerous countries including the United Kingdom, Israel, Russia, Japan, and Poland with the majority being from the Northeastern and Mid-Atlantic United States. The programs cover the late 1800s through the late 1900s with the majority of items from the 1940s through the 1960s.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The John Barnes Performing Arts Collection was given to Special Collections prior to 2009.
Biographical Information
John Hancock Barnes was born October 18, 1905 in Missouri and died on November 7, 1979 in Charlottesville, Virginia. He was married to Margaret Seymour. Barnes held both a Bachelor of Philosophy and a Master of Education. He was the head of the English department at Fluvanna County High School in Palmyra, Virginia from 1945 to 1949. He was an English teacher at Lane High School in Charlottesville, VA from 1949 until the school shut down under the Stanley Plan in September 1958 to protest the U.S. Supreme Court ruling regarding racial integration in Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka. When the school reopened in February 1959, Barnes was the guidance director. He remained in that position until at least 1963. He passed away in 1979.
Scope and Content
The collection includes performing arts programs from around the world as well as scrapbooks and clippings about the theatre and movie industries. The programs cover a variety of genres including theatre, classical and popular music, opera, ballet, motion picture, and other genres such as horse ballet, ice skating, and circus. The programs come from numerous countries including the United Kingdom, Israel, Russia, Japan, and Poland with the majority being from the Northeastern and Mid-Atlantic United States. The programs cover the late 1800s through the late 1900s with the majority of items from the 1940s through the 1960s. Many of the programs were paired with clippings of newspaper critics' reviews of the performances. The reviews have been digitized and are available upon request. See the Arrangement note for additional information on the contents of the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in ten series. For the most part, the series reflect the arrangement in which the collection was found in 2009. Please note: Many series overlap, i.e. there are theatre materials in series other than Series V.
Series I: Scrapbooks includes scrapbooks on a variety of theatre topics from the 1900s through the 1970s including articles on burlesque, Allied Entertainment, the Kansas City Theatre, Gloria Swanson, Charles Dickens, George Bernard Shaw, William Shakespeare, Christopher Marlowe, Ben Johnson, and the theatre industry in general. There are also scrapbooks containing theatrical programs from the 1920s to the 1970s.
Series II: Clippings consists of numerous magazine and journal articles from 1839 through 1966 about the theatre and entertainment industries that have been clipped and individually bound. Source publications for the clippings include: Popular Electricity, Munsey’s Magazine, Atlantic Monthly, The Library Magazine, Harper’s New Monthly Magazine, The Nineteenth Century, and more.
Series III: National Theatre (Washington, DC) includes performing arts programs from the National Theatre in Washington, DC. The series includes programs from the 1940s through the 1970s and opera programs from the mid-1940s. The majority of the series is theatrical programs which are grouped into by time period and program design. There are two subseries: 1940s-1950s playbills, 1960s-1970s playbills.
Series IV: John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts includes theatre, opera, ballet, kabuki, and concert programs. About half of the series is theatre programs covering the 1960s and 1970s. Programs for the other genres are all from the 1970s. The series has two subseries: theatre playbills and ballet programs.
Series V: Theatre includes a broad variety of theatrical programs from around the world including programs from Israel, Italy, Poland, France, and the United States. It also includes newsletters, advertising and subscription materials, and souvenir programs. There are seven subseries: George Bernard Shaw playbills, Chicago theatre playbills, Broadway playbills (further divided by era), Arena Stage playbills, The Virginia Players playbills, The Washington Theater Club playbills, and Souvenir programs. The remaining playbills are organized by venue. Items in this series are from the 1900s through the 1970s.
Series VI: Opera includes opera programs from the 1920s to the 1970s in English, French, and Italian. The programs are organized by opera company. Companies represented in the collection include: the English National Opera, Opera National de Belgique, the Dallas Civic Opera Company, The Oratorio Society of Charlottesville-Albemarle, the Virginia Opera Association, the Washington Grand Opera Association, and more.
Series VII: Ballet and Dance includes ballet and dance programs from the 1930s to 1980 in English, French, Polish, and Russian. The programs are organized by dance company. Companies represented in the collection include: Alvin Ailey City Center Dance Theater, Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, Bat-Dor Dance Company of Israel, Charlottesville Civic Ballet Company, The Bolshoi Ballet, Fairfax Ballet Company, National Ballet of Canada, New York City Ballet, State Order of Lenin Academic Opera and Ballet Theatre, The National Ballet (United States of America), and more.
Series VIII: Music includes concert programs for ensemble performances, individual performers, music festivals, and music variety shows. The programs are from the 1920s through the early 1980s. There are programs from the University of Virginia, Virginia Tech, the National Symphony Orchestra, the Civic Musical Association of Richmond, The Community Concert Association (Charlottesville, Virginia), and more. There are three subseries: University of Virginia programs, Virginia Tech Union programs, and Large musical ensemble programs.
Series IX: Motion Pictures and Television includes film materials from the 1920s through the 1970s with the majority of the items from the early days of film in the 1920s and 1930s. The series includes promotional handouts, film festival notes, motion picture brochures, catalogs, and programs, and a subseries of materials from the British Film Institute in the 1950s and 1960s. This series includes items in English, German, and Hungarian.
Series X: Other Genres includes items about the entertainment industry in general, museum and library event programs, circus programs, cabaret programs, figure skating programs, and a dressage (horse dancing) program. Items in this series are from the 1930s through the 1970s and are in English, Russian, and French.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
The following materials were removed from the collection and cataloged for the Special Collections Rare Book Collection:
Anna Bolena Italian-English Libretto, 1973
The Bookman's Journal and Print Collector, Vol. V, no. 1-3, 1921?
Player's Magazine, November 1924-May and June 1931, February-May 1959
Philharmonic, July 1901
Saint Joan feature book, 1957
Tiefland Libretto, 1908
A Witch of Salem Libretto, 1926
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Community theater
Geographical Names:
Charlottesville (Va.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Theater programs; Concert programs
Persons:
Barnes, John H. (John Hancock), 1905-1979
Contents List
- Series I: Scrapbooks, c.1900-1970s
  - Theatrical scrapbooks 1-2 c.1900-1930s (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Theatrical scrapbook 3 c.1900-1930s (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Theatrical scrapbook 4 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Theatrical scrapbook 5 1940s (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Gloria Swanson scrapbook; Burlesque and Allied Entertainment scrapbook 1950s (Box-folder 1-5)
  - The Kansas City Theatre and Other Theatrical Subjects scrapbooks 1920s-1950s (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Dickens Theatrical Scrapbook Volume I 1920s-1960s (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Shaw Theatrical Scrapbook Volumes I & II 1940s-1970s (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Shakespearean Theatre scrapbooks Volumes I & II 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Early English Drama Scrapbook Volumes I & II 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Christopher Marlowe scrapbook; Ben Johnson scrapbook 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes I & II 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes III & IV 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes V & VI 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes VII & VIII 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes IX & X 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Theatre Programs scrapbooks Volumes XI & XII 1920s-1970s (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Author bibliographies n.d. (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Theatrical scrapbook clippings 1910s (Box-folder 2-9)
- Series II: Clippings, 1839-1966
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1876, 1887, 1892, 1909, 1957 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1867, 1886, 1905-1906, 1930, 1955 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1877, 1885, 1907, 1916, 1930 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1867, 1912-1913, 1924, 1973 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1880s, 1910s (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1839-1917, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1867-1925, 1959-1960, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1850-1888, 1900-1915, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Clippings: magazine and journal articles about the theatre industry 1858, 1877-1915, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Series III: National Theatre (Washington, DC), 1940s-1970s
  - Single-sheet theatre playbills 1940s (Box-folder 4-1)
  - 1940s-1950s theatre playbills 1943-1961
    - Theatre playbills 1943-1961 (Box-folder 4-2)
    - Theatre playbills 1943-1961 (Box-folder 4-3)
    - Theatre playbills 1943-1961 (Box-folder 4-4)
    - Theatre playbills 1943-1961 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - 1960s-1970s theatre playbills 1962-1983
    - Show titles 0-A 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-6)
    - Show titles B-C 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-7)
    - Show titles D-E 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-8)
    - Show titles F-G 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-9)
    - Show titles H 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-10)
    - Show titles I-L 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-11)
    - Show titles M 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-12)
    - Show titles N-O 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-13)
    - Show titles P-R 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-14)
    - Show titles S-Z 1962-1983 (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Opera programs 1943-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 4-16)
- Series IV: John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1960s-1970s
  - Theatre playbills 1972-1983
    - Show titles 0-B 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-17)
    - Show titles C-D 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-18)
    - Show titles E-G 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-19)
    - Show titles H-L 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-20)
    - Show titles M 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-21)
    - Show titles N-S 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-22)
    - Show titles T-W 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4-23)
  - Opera programs 1971-1975, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 4-24)
  - Ballet programs 1971-1981
    - The Bolshoi Ballet programs 1975 (Box-folder 5-1)
    - The National Ballet (United States of America) programs 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5-2)
    - The Royal Ballet (Denmark) program 1976 (Box-folder 5-3)
    - New York City Ballet programs 1976-1978 (Box-folder 5-4)
    - The Stuttgart Ballet program 1977 (Box-folder 5-5)
    - American Ballet Theatre programs 1974-1978 (Box-folder 5-6)
  - Kabuki program 1977 (Box-folder 5-7)
  - Concert programs 1971-1976, 1981 (Box-folder 5-8)
- Series V: Theatre, 1900s-1970s
  - Kabuki program 1966 (Box-folder 5-9)
  - Dinner theatre playbills 1970s (Box-folder 5-10)
  - George Bernard Shaw playbills 1930-1979
    - Show titles A-H 1930, 1937, 1950-1961, 1967-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 5-11)
    - Show titles M-Y 1946-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 5-12)
  - Chicago theatre playbills 1927-1983
    - Show titles A-H 1927-1983 (Box-folder 5-13)
    - Show titles L-P 1927-1983 (Box-folder 5-14)
    - Show titles R-W 1927-1983 (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Broadway playbills 1922-1981
    - 1920s playbills 1922-1930
      - Show titles A-H 1922-1930 (Box-folder 5-16)
      - Show titles I-R 1925-1930 (Box-folder 5-17)
      - Show titles S-Z c.1923-1930 (Box-folder 5-18)
    - 1930s-1950s playbills 1932-1956
      - Show titles A-E 1932-1956 (Box-folder 5-19)
      - Show titles G-L 1932-1956 (Box-folder 5-20)
      - Show titles M-O 1932-1956 (Box-folder 5-21)
      - Show titles P-T 1932-1956 (Box-folder 5-22)
      - Show titles V-W 1932-1956 (Box-folder 5-23)
    - 1960s-1970s playbills 1960-1981
      - Show titles 0-A 1960-1981 (Box-folder 5-24)
      - Show titles B-C 1960-1981 (Box-folder 5-25)
      - Show titles D-E 1960-1981 (Box-folder 5-26)
      - Show titles F-G 1960-1981 (Box-folder 5-27)
      - Show titles H-I 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-1)
      - Show titles J-M 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-2)
      - Show titles M 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-3)
      - Show titles N-P 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-4)
      - Show titles R-S 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-5)
      - Show titles T-V 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-6)
      - Show titles W-Z 1960-1981 (Box-folder 6-7)
  - 4 County Players playbills c.1975 (Box-folder 6-8)
  - Abbey Players playbill 1933 (Folder 1)
  - Academy Theatre (Johannesburg, South Africa) playbill c.1975 (Box-folder 6-9)
  - Albemarle High School playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-10)
  - Albemarle Players playbills 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 6-11)
  - Alhambra Theatre (Tel-Aviv, Israel) playbill c.1966 (Box-folder 6-12)
  - Alvin Theatre playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-13)
  - Americana Summer Stock playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-14)
  - American Association of University Women (Charlottesville, Virginia) playbill 1974 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - The American Shakespeare Festival and Academy playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-16)
  - The American Theater (Washington, District of Columbia) playbill 1973 (Box-folder 6-17)
  - American University playbill c.1970-1971 (Box-folder 6-18)
  - Arena Stage playbills 1960s-1970s
    - Show titles 0-D 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 6-19)
    - Show titles E-M 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 6-20)
    - Show titles N-S 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 6-21)
    - Show titles T-Z and Multiple Show playbills 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 6-22)
  - Barter Theatre: The State Theatre of Virginia playbills 1948-1950, 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 6-23)
  - Bridgeport Playhouse playbill 1940 (Box-folder 6-24)
  - Broadway Theatre League of San Diego playbill 1963 (Box-folder 6-25)
  - Brown Theatre (Louisville, Kentucky) playbills 1963 (Box-folder 6-26)
  - Bucks County Playhouse playbill 1958 (Box-folder 6-27)
  - Captain Lew Pierce's Show Boat playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-28)
  - Carter Barron Amphitheater playbills n.d. (Box-folder 6-29)
  - The Catholic Club of Georgetown playbill 1960 (Box-folder 6-30)
  - The Catholic University of America playbills 1948-1977 (Box-folder 6-31)
  - Center Theatre (Norfolk, Virginia) playbill 1962 (Box-folder 6-32)
  - Cherry Lane Theatre playbill and Clippings 1960s (Box-folder 6-33)
  - Circle Arts Theatre playbills 1960s (Box-folder 6-34)
  - Civic Theatre (San Diego, California) playbills 1960s (Box-folder 6-35)
  - Cleveland Playhouse Summer Theatre playbills 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6-36)
  - The Cleveland State University playbill 1971 (Box-folder 6-37)
  - Columbia Theatre playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-38)
  - Comedy Theatre (London, England) 1973 (Box-folder 6-39)
  - Cox Theatre playbill 1944 (Box-folder 6-40)
  - Dock Street Theatre playbill 1947 (Box-folder 6-41)
  - El Cortez Hotel playbill 1960 (Box-folder 6-42)
  - Ellen Stewart Theatre playbill 1970 (Box-folder 6-43)
  - Follies Bergère playbills n.d. (Box-folder 6-44)
  - Ford's Theatre playbills 1968-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 6-45)
  - Gallaudet College playbills 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6-46)
  - Gregory Enterprises, Inc. playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-47)
  - Hartman Theatre playbill 1926 (Box-folder 6-48)
  - Heritage Repertory Theatre playbills 1974-1976 (Box-folder 6-49)
  - Hexagon Club playbill 1964 (Box-folder 6-50)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies in the Theatre Arts playbills 1963 (Box-folder 6-51)
  - Jefferson Post American Legion playbill 1930s (Folder 1)
  - Kings Theatre (Edinburgh, Scotland) 1971 (Box-folder 6-52)
  - La Jolla Playhouse playbills 1955-1957, 1962 (Box-folder 6-53)
  - Lane High School playbills 1947-1970 (Box-folder 6-54)
  - London Traverse Theatre Company playbill 1967 (Box-folder 6-55)
  - Lyceum Theatre (East Orange, New Jersey) playbill 1930-1931 (Box-folder 6-56)
  - Lyric Theatre (London, England) playbill 1973 (Box-folder 6-57)
  - Lyric Theatre (Richmond, Virginia) playbills 1946, n.d. (Box-folder 6-58)
  - Maplewood Theatre (Maplewood, New Jersey) playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-59)
  - Marymount International School playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-60)
  - Mill Mountain Playhouse playbill n.d. (Box-folder 6-61)
  - The Mosque Theatre (Richmond, Virginia) playbills n.d. (Box-folder 6-62)
  - Musical Celebrities, Inc. playbills 1958-1967 (Box-folder 6-63)
  - Music Hall Center for the Performing Arts playbill 1975 (Box-folder 6-64)
  - New York State Theater playbill 1967 (Box-folder 7-1)
  - Old Globe Theatre (San Diego, California) playbills 1958-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 7-2)
  - Olney Theatre playbills 1972 (Box-folder 7-3)
  - Parker Playhouse playbill 1968 (Box-folder 7-4)
  - Pasadena Playhouse Association playbill 1937 (Box-folder 7-5)
  - Radford College playbill 1970s (Box-folder 7-6)
  - The Raleigh Little Theatre playbill 1960 (Box-folder 7-7)
  - Randolph Macon Woman's College playbill 1947 (Box-folder 7-8)
  - The Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center playbill 1967 (Box-folder 7-9)
  - The Roanoke Island Historical Association, Inc. playbill 1954 (Box-folder 7-10)
  - Roanoke Summer Theatre playbill 1964 (Box-folder 7-11)
  - Royal Shakespeare Company (London, England) playbill 1974 (Box-folder 7-12)
  - The Shoreview Hotel playbill n.d. (Box-folder 7-13)
  - St. Albans Repertory Theater playbill n.d. (Box-folder 7-14)
  - The Stagers of Deerfield playbill 1963 (Box-folder 7-15)
  - Syracuse University playbills 1933-1934 (Box-folder 7-16)
  - Sam S. Shubert Theater (Washington, District of Columbia) playbill 1959 (Box-folder 7-17)
  - San Francisco Civic Light Opera playbill 1977 (Box-folder 7-18)
  - Shady Grove Music Theatre playbill c.1977 (Box-folder 7-19)
  - The Showtimers playbill 1964 (Box-folder 7-20)
  - Shubert Theatre (Newark, New Jersey) playbills 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7-21)
  - Skaneateles Summer Theatre playbills 1937-1940 (Box-folder 7-22)
  - Source Theatre Company playbill c.1977 (Box-folder 7-23)
  - Star-Light Opera Balboa Park Bowl playbills 1950s (Box-folder 7-24)
  - Stratford Festival Canada playbills 1969 (Box-folder 7-25)
  - Theater Wagon playbill n.d. (Box-folder 7-26)
  - Theatre 80 St. Marks playbill 1970 (Box-folder 7-27)
  - The Theatre at Saint Peter's Church playbill 1983 (Box-folder 7-28)
  - Theatre Lobby (Washington, District of Columbia) playbills 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 7-29)
  - Theatro Del Ridotto playbill 1967 (Box-folder 7-30)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Unitarian Church (Charlottesville, Virginia) playbills 1955-1956, n.d. (Box-folder 7-31)
  - University of Denver playbill 1965 (Box-folder 7-32)
  - The University of San Diego playbills 1960, n.d. (Box-folder 7-33)
  - University of Virginia playbills 1940s-1980s (Box-folder 7-34)
  - The Virginia Players playbills 1947-1982, n.d.
    - Show titles A-M 1947-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 7-35)
    - Show titles N-Z and multiple show playbills 1947-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 7-36)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University playbills 1973-1974, 1982-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 7-37)
  - The Washington Theater Club playbills 1960s-1970s
    - Show titles A-M 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 7-38)
    - Show titles N-Z 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 7-39)
  - Writers Stage Theatre playbill n.d. (Box-folder 7-40)
  - Virginia Museum Theatre playbills 1966, 1981 (Box-folder 7-41)
  - Virginia Museum Theatre playbills 1971, n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Vivian Beaumont Theater playbill 1968 (Box-folder 7-42)
  - Warner Theatre (Washington, District of Columbia) playbill 1980 (Box-folder 7-43)
  - Washington Performing Arts Society playbill 1968 (Box-folder 7-44)
  - Wayne State University Theatre playbill 1962 (Box-folder 7-45)
  - Westport Country Playhouse playbills 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7-46)
  - Wolf Trap Farm Park for the Performing Arts Filene Center playbill 1971 (Box-folder 7-47)
  - WRVA Theatre playbills 1956, 1960 (Box-folder 7-48)
  - York Theatre Royal (York, England) playbill 1971 (Box-folder 7-49)
  - Theatre and entertainment newsletters 1945, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7-50)
  - Theatre advertising and subscription materials 1920s-1980s (Box-folder 7-51)
  - Theatre advertising and subscription materials 1920s-1980s (Box-folder 7-52)
  - Theatre advertising and subscription materials 1920s-1980s (Box-folder 7-53)
  - Souvenir programs 1900-c.1970
    - Show titles 0-D 1900-c.1970 (Box-folder 7-54)
    - Show titles F-K 1900-c.1970 (Box-folder 7-55)
    - Show titles M-P 1900-c.1970 (Box-folder 7-56)
    - Show titles R-W and theatre festivals 1900-c.1970 (Box-folder 7-57)
- Series VI: Opera, 1920s-1970s
  - Chautauqua Opera Association program 1973 (Box-folder 8-1)
  - Chicago Civic Opera Company programs 1937-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 8-2)
  - Chicago Grand Opera Company programs 1934-1935 (Box-folder 8-3)
  - Civic Musical Association of Richmond program 1943 (Box-folder 8-4)
  - The Columbia Symphony Orchestra and Chorus program 1962 (Box-folder 8-5)
  - The Connecticut Opera Association programs 1944, n.d. (Box-folder 8-6)
  - Dallas Civic Opera Company program 1958 (Box-folder 8-7)
  - Mrs. Dorsey's Concert Bureau program 1941-1942 (Box-folder 8-8)
  - English National Opera program 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8-9)
  - The German Grand Opera Company program 1929 (Box-folder 8-10)
  - Goldovsky Opera Theater program 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8-11)
  - Kansas City Little Symphony Orchestra program 1923 (Box-folder 8-12)
  - Metropolitan Opera (New York, New York) programs 1925-1981 (Box-folder 8-13)
  - New York City Opera programs 1974-1978 (Box-folder 8-14)
  - Opera National de Belgique program 1976 (Box-folder 8-15)
  - The Oratorio Society of Charlottesville-Albemarle program 1976 (Box-folder 8-16)
  - Philadelphia La Scala Opera Company programs 1945-1946 (Box-folder 8-17)
  - Ravinia Company programs 1927 (Box-folder 8-18)
  - Royal Opera (England) programs 1971 (Box-folder 8-19)
  - San Carlo Opera Company programs 1941-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 8-20)
  - Teatro Dell'opera programs 1966, 1975 (Box-folder 8-21)
  - Theatres Lyriques Nationaux program 1961-1962 (Box-folder 8-22)
  - Turnau Opera Players program 1962 (Box-folder 8-23)